Hari Kishore

Software Engineer -2

Application developer with 4 years of overall experience building and maintaining a production-level large-scale micro-services based and standalone web application, on modern technologies and cloud, with ability to quickly learn and work on new technology.

harikishore025@gmail.com

harikishorepec.github.io/new

github.com/HariKishorePec

+91 7004815015

in linkedin.com/in/hari-kishore-pec

stackoverflow.com/users/11887348/kishore

WORK EXPERIENCED

Engineer 2 - Full Stack

Verizon India

07/2023 - Present

Benaaluru

- Owned the design and devlopement of UI for SNM application for NP2.0 project.
- Mirgrated struts-JSP project to react.
- Created 30+ react UI component for internal project, integration with backend services. *Tech stack:* React, Node, Express, swagger, oracle DB.
- Build and deployment to k8s. Tech stack: Docker, Kubernetes, podman.

Associate Application Developer Lifion by ADP

09/2020 - 06/2023 Chennai

- Contributed towards real time search and reporting capabilities of Lifion Platform, and the search DSL/DSL wrapper for advanced search. Tech Stack: NodeJS, Elasticsearch, TypeScript, PostgresQL
- Created and contributed towards UI service for advanced search powered by AWS EMR and PySpark, using ReactJS and NodeJS and integrated with Monaco Editor. Tech Stack: NodeJS, ReactJS, MaterialUI. Elasticsearch, CSS
- Contribution toward DSL wrapper for advanced search using Antlr, that gives user capability write queries in SQL like language which is converted to Search DSL. *Tech Stack:* NodeJS, TypeScript, Antlr
- Implemented Ratelimit using Ambassador, being the first team across lifion to do so. Tech Stack: Helm, Ambassador, Kubernetes
- Performed performance benchmarking using K6 for service endpoints, by creating multiple pods with different CPU and memory limits. TechStack: K6,Node
- Configured additional Datadog monitors, required alerts and dashboards to monitor the platform. Tech Stack: Datadog
- Contribution towards Advanced search powered by PySpark and AWS EMR. Tech Stack: AWS EMR, PySpark, S3, Python, django
- Contribution towards Advance search powered by AWS Neptune.
 Tech Stack: GraphQL/gremlin, NodeJS
- Contribution toward worker service. stack: Golang

Software Development Intern

ADP India

01/2020 - 08/2020

- Created APIs in Nodejs for one of our services (search service) by fetching data from Elasticsearch. Updated Swagger docs related to concerning APIs.
- Responsible for writing scripts for custom reports.
- Tech stack: NodeJS, Rest APIs, Swagger UI, MySQL, Jest.

EDUCATION

B.Tech - Computer Science and EngineeringPondicherry Engineering College

SKILLS



PERSONAL PROJECTS

BSE Scrapper - Python, Docker, MySql

• A dockerized app for fetching BSE data using python, beautifulsoup, mysql.

College Website Renovation

- Renovation of Our College website, PEC (Now PTU). It was a collaborative project, Contributed as frontend lead and responsible for responsiveness and overall frontend for our website. <u>Deployment</u>
- Tech Stack/Tools: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap 4, JavaScript, AJAX, Php

ICON Website - A Website for department fest (02/2019 - 03/2019)

o Design and Development of website for our department fest deployed successfully during 3rd year. GitHub $\ ^{\square}$

ACHIEVEMENTS

'Established User' privilege on Stack overflow with 3.0m impact/reach and 2.0k+ reputation points.

Earned by contributing on Stackoverflow community, answered 45+ question, with 2 gold, 18 silver and 28 bronze badges.

GATE Qualified - Computer Science (2020)

1st place in "Code debugging" competition at PEC (09/2018)

A National level symposium organised by Dept. of EIE, Pondicherry Engineering

1st prize in "Techno Crunch" competition among students of all four years (03/2018)

Organised by Computer and Multimedia Club, PEC

08/2016 - 06/2020 CGPA: 7.87